The first cells actually appear around the 18th day, the blood cells.
Three important parts.
The origin will come from the yolk sac, which integrates with the blood.
This is where we find what are called primitive megaloblasts.
This lasts for the first two months.
At the beginning of the first month, a second movement arises from the liver.
The blood will develop from the liver.
And it is only around the third month that there is a part that begins.
to be produced in the bone marrow. So we could say we develop anew from
the periphery to the center. Umbilico-pedal period,
hepatic period, and here it will be a period
we could say at the level of red blood cells. The only remnant that will remain
from this development
will be the mesenteric artery. It served as a
pivot point, a fulcrum for the rotation.
of the development of the intestinal loop at the moment when I have my amniotic cavity making this all
around, at the same time I have my yolk sac
which is there containing the original cells
for circulation doing this and reintegrating
partly with the yolk sac
embryonic membrane forming the umbilical colon with the placenta and the
remnant that will connect,
this is the superior mesenteric system.
Rotation axis
very important for embryonic development.
When looking at the heart,
you have the aortic arch.
Symbolically, we can say it goes up
or down.
Your right hand like this,
this represents
the movement of the heart.
In its beating, which repeats, it is almost a developmental movement.
The aortic arch, it creates in the movement of the heart a
twist or untwist motion.
At the moment the heart pushes, the aortic arch opens to
absorb the blood.
At the moment it descends, it empties making a movement like this.
So at the moment it does like this, the aortic arch,
opens to take the blood and closes to eject it.
So we must connect the aortic arch to the heart, in function.
So it's a bit like people playing basketball.
At the moment I rise,
that's when the aorta ejects its volume.
You know the aorta contains in its volume almost as much blood as there is in the heart,
on the arterial level, you see.
And so this means the aorta participates.
in systolic ejection, but remember that it's supported by the fascial environment,
by the fishnet stocking. You have the aortic arch, you
have the bronchial bifurcation,
and you have another part which is the esophagus. They are connected by
this common fascia,
which holds them together. This is called the point of the rhythmic zone. 100
000 beats
of the heart.
24 hours, 23 thousand breaths in 24 hours 1000
to 2000 swallowings, it's a large rhythmic area
that comes together and connects between
three of the four and five which are
a balance plan on a fascial plane of the rhythmic cardio
pleuro-digestive zone. I have the rise
here, I have the heart here and at the bottom there will be a very
important bifurcation here which we
call the iliac arteries, and here at the top I will have another level but in fact this
forms
a pure unitary plane. We see that in certain pathologies of
the coxofemoral type or
anything, this can destabilize the heart and conversely what happens here in the phases
of rotation here can manifest
up to the level of the heart.